SOFIA REIS

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Born in Portugal, 7 August 1994

sofia.o.reis@tecnico.ulisboa.pt email

https://sofiaoreis.github.io/ website

phone +351 919 760 820

() · (D) · y social media

віо

PhD Student in Software Engineering and Security at Instituto Superior Técnico, University of Lisbon and researcher at INESC-ID. Studying automated techniques to detect security software vulnerabilities. I also perform research in software maintainability, software fault localization and slicing. Active member of the QUASAR research group (TQRG).

EDUCATION

2018-2022 Instituto Superior Técnico, University of Lisbon

PhD in Computer Science and Engineering GPA: 19.4/20 · Waiting for PhD proposal defense

Thesis: Understanding and Improving Security-oriented Static Analysis Techniques

Advisor: Prof. Rui Abreu

2016-2017 Leiden Institute of Advanced Computer Science

ERASMUS+ **PROGRAMME**

GPA: 7.5/10 · Computer Science and Advanced Data Analytics

Data Mining, Social Network Analysis, Big Data and Evolutionary Algorithms

Reference: Prof. Rosaldo Rossetti · rossetti@fe.up.pt

2012-2017 Faculty of Engineering of the University of Porto

BSc+MSc(Integrated Master)

GPA: 15/20 · Informatics and Computing Engineering (A3ES accreditation) Thesis: Assessing software vulnerabilities using Naturally Occurring Defects

Mark: 19/20 - top 5% of the best thesis in the class of 2017

Advisor: Prof. Rui Abreu

WORK EXPERIENCE

2018–Present Junior Researcher, INESC-ID — Lisbon

INESC-ID

Analysis of the entire corpus of documents published in the last 30 years in the Portuguese law search engine. Funded by the INCM under the ref. "353/2017 -Serviço de pesquisa em linha para o Diário da Republica eletrónico (DRE)"

Reference: José Borbinha · jlb@tecnico.ulisboa.pt

2017-2018 RPA Developer, KPMG PT — Porto

KPMG PT

Robotic Process Automation Developer. Responsible for designing and delivering automations in Automation Anywhere for VAT processing in the pharmaceutical sector. Reference: Lara Conceição and Daniel Pires Certified in Automation Anywhere. License: AAADVC-Fv5QqG1JlD

TEACHING ASSISTANT

1	EACHING ASSISIANT
	Future of Computing
Conference	1-day training on the Fundamentals of accelerated computing with CUDA Python . Certified by NVIDIA. Reference: Cristiana Dinea · cdinea@nvidia.com
	Spring 2019 Software Engineering
University	Full 6-month course. Instituto Superior Técnico, University of Lisbon, Alameda. Reference: Alberto Abad · alberto.abad@tecnico.ulisboa.pt
	Fall 2018 Foundations of Programming
	Full 6-month course. Instituto Superior Técnico, University of Lisbon, TagusPark. Reference: Rui Abreu · rui@computer.org
P	UBLICATIONS
2019	[1] Sofia Reis, Rui Abreu and Marcelo D'Amorim. 2019. Demystifying the Combination of Dynamic Slicing and Spectrum-based Fault Localization . International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI) · Conference Paper
2018	[2] Sofia Reis. 2018. Leveraging Known Vulnerabilities to Modernize Static Analysis Tools . PhD OpenDays 2018. Lisbon, Portugal · <i>Poster</i>
2017	[3] Sofia Reis and Rui Abreu. 2017. A Database of Existing Vulnerabilities to Enable Controlled Testing Studies . International Journal of Secure Software Engineering (IJSSE) 8 (3): 1-23 · <i>Journal Paper</i>
	[4] Sofia Reis and Rui Abreu. 2017. SECBENCH: A Database of Real Security Vulnerabilities . Secure Software Engineering in DevOps and Agile Development (SecSE), co-located with ESORICS, Oslo, Noruega · <i>Workshop Paper</i>
	[5] Sofia Reis and Rui Abreu. 2017. Using Github to Create a Dataset of Natural Occurring Vulnerabilities . International Workshop on Principles of Diagnosis (DX), Bréscia, Italy · <i>Abstract and Poster</i>
G	RANTS, HONORS AND AWARDS
2019	PhD Scholarship by FCT, cf. SFRH/BD/143319/2019 · 4 years
2018	Scholarship funded by FCT/MCTES through national funds (PIDDAC) under the project UID/CEC/50021/2013 to perform a Systematic Survey on Platforms for Continuous Inspection of Code Quality \cdot 6 months
R	ELEVANT TRAINING
2019	2-days Facebook Testing and Verification Symposium (FaceTAV), Facebook London, UK, November 2019 - accepted
2019	1-week Future of Computing Conference, Portugal, July 2019
2019	4-days VMCAI Summer School, Portugal, January 2019
2018	2-days Facebook Testing and Verification Symposium (FaceTAV), Facebook London, UK, November 2018 (invitation only)

OTHER INFORMATION

Communication Skills

2018 · Poster at PhD OpenDays 2018, Lisbon, Portugal

2017 · Poster at the International Workshop on Principles of Diagnosis (DX),

Bréscia, Italy

Volunteer

2019 · Future of Computing Conference (Porto, Portugal) · 1-week

2019 $\,\cdot\,$ ACM SIGPLAN Symposium on Principles of Programming Languages

(POPL'19, Lisbon, Portugal) · 1-week

2018 \cdot International Conference on Software Quality, Reliability and Security

(QRS'18, Lisbon, Portugal) · 3-days

2017 · Talk a Bit (Porto, Portugal) — organized by FEUP · 1-day

Committee

2019 · ICST2020 (Porto, Portugal): Sponsorship and social media · 1-week

2019 · Commit Porto (Porto, Portugal) — organized by AlumniEI-FEUP · 1-day

2018 · Commit Porto (Porto, Portugal) — organized by AlumniEI-FEUP · 1-day

Organization

2019 · Vice-President of AlumniEI-FEUP · 4-years

Languages

Portuguese · Mothertongue

English · Intermediate (fluent)

French · Basic · Basic

October 29, 2019